ALLEN BEN PHILIPOSE



DATA ENGINEER

WORK EXPERIENCE

ZS ASSOCIATES

DECISION ANALYTICS ASSOCIATE

JULY 2022 -

Worked on creating Pipelines for generating recommendations by processing weekly updated Real-World Data | Facilitated inter team process collaboration | Conducted sessions for Skill Development and Onboarding | Joined - January 2022

SKILLSHIP FOUNDATION

TECH LEAD (UI/UX)

NOV 2020 - AUG 2021

Assisted in onboarding new hires | Organized Technical Events for Juniors | Worked as the Design Lead for the official website | Worked as a Design Manager in the PR department | Mentored Project teams from Tech Domain | Joined - September 2020

IOTHINC - VIT

HEAD OF DESIGN

AUG 2020 - NOV 2021

Actively participated in student member recruitment | Created Design Programs for Juniors | Worked as the Lead for the official website | Mentored Projects from the Tech Domain | Core Member Role in Management | Organized IoThon | Joined - December 2019

SPARKS FOUNDATION

DATA SCIENCE INTERN

MAY 2021 - JUNE 2021

Built and fine-tuned learning models using Python | Collected, crunched and analyzed big data | Leveraged Business data to design visualization dashboards | Joined - May 2021

EDUCATION

VELLORE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY

CLASS OF 2022

Electronics and Communication Engineering with specialization in IoT and Sensors | CGPA: 8.87 | Senior Core Member @IEEE RAS | Senior Core Member @IEEE ComSoc

DELHI PUBLIC SCHOOL, BANGALORE EAST

CBSE - XII

CLASS OF 2018

Physics - Chemistry - Mathematics - Computer Science | Bass Guitarist in Rock Band | Board Percentage: 82.80%

BALDWIN BOYS' HIGH SCHOOL

ICSE - X

CLASS OF 2016

Science - Computer Science | Rock Band Member | Vice Band Major | Board Percentage: 89.33%

PROJECTS

EMERGENCY VEHICLE DETECTION

2020

An efficient way to clear a path for an oncoming emergency vehicle using video surveillance and TensorFlow models

GOD'S EYE

2021

An advanced security system automated to trigger alerts and track suspects based on ReID using image processing

RACISM 2020

SENTIMENT

ANALYSIS ON

A study on the uproar caused by police brutality on George Floyd using web scraping and NLTK text analysis

CROWD STOCK **MANAGEMENT**

2021

Interpreting crowd density using data analytics and optimizing movement by congestion alert and re-route method

TRADING CHATBOT

2020

Dialog-flow based project for stock price observation, alerting and auto transaction

AUTO IRRIGATION

2021

Prediction of soil moisture using a multi-feature regression model and scraped values of other parameters

INTERESTS

Swimmer | Musician | Designer | Numismatist | Coder | Stock Trader

+91 9449277201

allenbphilip@gmail.com https://abphilip.com/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/allenbphilip/ B001, SLS SUNNY GARDENS, 5TH MAIN, WASA LAYOUT, BANGALORE - 37

PROFILE

Hello, I'm Allen.

Analyst at ZS. I have completed Electronics and Communication Engineering with a specialization in IoT and Sensors from VIT, the batch of 2022.

Me in 4 words?

Proactive. Productive. Persistent. Passionate.

I'm a Big data analyst, a graphic designer, a front-end developer, and a cloud solution architecting enthusiast, actively trying to enhance my expertise and explore learning opportunities in these domains.

SKILLS

- Data Engineering Apache Spark. Hive. Hadoop. PySpark.
- Cloud Architecture and **Development** Google Cloud Platform (GCP). Amazon Web Services (AWS). IBM BlueMix. Firebase.
- Machine Learning Natural Language Processing. Digital Image Processing. Tensorflow. ML Models. Sci-kit Learn.
- UI/UX Figma. Adobe XD.

ThingSpeak.

- Graphic Designing Illustrator, After Effects. Premiere Pro. Audition. Photoshop.
- Front-end Development HTML. CSS. JavaScript. Bootstrap4.
- Programming Languages Python. Java. SQL. Git. C. C++. BASH. Assembly. VerilogHDL.
- Electronics Arduino. Atmel AVR. Keil. Multisim. PCB. LabView.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1 x AWS Certified
- 8 x HackerRank Certifications
- 14 x LinkedIn Skill Badges
- 15+ NASSCOM Skill Badges
- 30+ Google Cloud Skill Badges
- 40+ Coursera Certifications
- 40+ Percipio Certifications 50+ LinkedIn Certifications
- 7 x 5* HackerRank Badges
- 3* Profile at CodeChef